Muhui Yu (Grace)

Product Designer & Engineer

muhuiyu.github.io linkedin.com/in/muhuiyu/ muhuiyu.grace@gmail.com +65 89516033

SUMMARY

I am a Product Designer with Computer Science and research background. I held positions across different industries, including mental health app, enterprise HR management, chatbot builder SaaS, flight social media app, etc. I also built additional design and engineering capabilities via side projects, mentorship, onsite event, and other volunteering efforts.

I focus on user research, mobile/web design, prototyping, and usability testing. I'm able to take ideas from concept to wireframe to prototype to production (React and Swift).

EXPERIENCE

Intellect.co / Product Designer Lead

Feb 2021 - Present, Singapore

Led design team to conduct research, design, prototyping, usability testing for a mental health mobile app.

Collaborated with product and engineering team to maintain an internal style guide, implement new design pattens, UX writing and branding persona.

SeaGroup / UX Product Designer

Jun 2019 - Jan 2021, Singapore

Led the research, prototyping, usability testing, and design an enterprise collaboration platform on web, desktop and mobile.

Collaborated with product design team to maintain an internal style guide, implement new design pattens, UX writing and branding persona.

Contributed as a designer and researcher, working closely with product managers, developers and the marketing team, to better user experience.

BotBonnie / UI/UX Designer & Full-Stack Engineer Intern

Sep 2018 - Apr 2019, Taiwan

Conducted research and design for users on a chatbot builder platform. Designed, developed and launched a company backend system (including design and full-stack).

Academia Sinica / Research Assistant

Jul 2017 - Sep 2018, Taiwan

Published at IEEE BigComp 2019 and IEEE Pacific 2018. Clinched the first prize in Pixnet 2017 Hackathon by researching in Chinese Recommendation Chatbot.

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Computer Science / National Taiwan University

2014 - 2018, Taiwan

Specialized in Natural Language Processing & Deep Learning. Worked as a Graphic Designer and Web Designer & Developer in lab to build lab website. Clinched 1st prize in NTUCS student research competition by researching on emotion-aware chatbot and lyric generator.

SKILLS

Design: Strategy & vision presentations · UI graphics · User Research · User flows · Wireframes & mockups · Usability Testing · Style guides & design pattern system

 $\textbf{Tools} \colon \mathsf{Figma} \cdot \mathsf{Sketch} \cdot \mathsf{Xcode} \cdot \mathsf{Adobe}$

Development: HTML/CSS/JS · React.js · Node.js · Swift · Python

Others: Natural Language Process ·
Deep Learning · Reinforcement
Learning · Dialogue System · Tensorflow

LANGUAGE

Mandarin, English, Japanese, Vietnamese